{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Physical Science",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "History of the Atom",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "Who first introduced the idea of the atom?",
      "answer": "Leucippus and Democritus",
      "choices": [
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton",
        "Leucippus and Democritus",
        "Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the basic unit of matter and a chemical element?",
      "answer": "Atom",
      "choices": [
        "Element",
        "Atom",
        "Matter",
        "Mixture"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who believed that there was a limit to how far matter could be broken down into smaller pieces?",
      "answer": "Leucippus",
      "choices": [
        "Democritus",
        "Leucippus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who gave the smallest component of matter the name \"atomos\"?",
      "answer": "Democritus",
      "choices": [
        "Leucippus",
        "Democritus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who believed that the world was made of earth, air, fire, and water?",
      "answer": "Aristotle",
      "choices": [
        "Democritus",
        "Leucippus",
        "Aristotle",
        "Dalton"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Atomic Theory"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the father of modern chemistry?",
      "answer": "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
      "choices": [
        "Robert Boyle",
        "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
        "John Dalton",
        "J.J. Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the earliest practices of chemical science?",
      "answer": "Alchemy",
      "choices": [
        "Chemistry",
        "Science",
        "Alchemy",
        "Mythology"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "Early Chemistry"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who published \"The Skeptical Chymist\" in 1661?",
      "answer": "Robert Boyle",
      "choices": [
        "Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier",
        "Robert Boyle",
        "John Dalton",
        "J.J. Thomson"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What theory states that all matter is made up of atoms- extremely minute, indestructible, and indivisible particle?",
      "answer": "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
      "choices": [
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Modern Atomic Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What theory states that atoms can neither be created nor destroyed?",
      "answer": "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
      "choices": [
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Dalton's Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Modern Atomic Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who discovered that atoms consists of electrons through the cathode ray tube experiment?",
      "answer": "J.J Thomson",
      "choices": [
        "John Dalton",
        "J.J Thomson",
        "Ernest Rutherford",
        "Robert Boyle"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What model of the atom is also known as the nuclear model?",
      "answer": "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
      "choices": [
        "Dalton's Atomic Model",
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Plum Pudding Model"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    },
    {
      "question": "What model proposes that an atom has a small, dense, positively charged nucleus at its center, with electrons orbiting this nucleus?",
      "answer": "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
      "choices": [
        "Dalton's Atomic Model",
        "Thomson Atomic Theory",
        "Rutherford's Model of Atom",
        "Plum Pudding Model"
      ],
      "reference": "HISTORY-OF-ATOM.pdf",
      "term": "19th Century Models"
    }
  ]
}